<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Accountant by Day</title>
    <link>http://accountantbyday.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Accountant by Day</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://accountantbyday.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://accountantbyday.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://accountantbyday.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AccountantByDay is made with Hugo.
Hugo is a static site engine written in Go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trucking along</title>
      <link>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2016-05-28-trucking-along/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2016-05-28-trucking-along/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The road to financial independence is pretty boring at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;Contribute enough to 401(k) to get employer match



&lt;ul&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;Done.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;/li&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;Pay off all high-interest debt



&lt;ul&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;Paid off student loans in 2013&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;/li&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;Build an emergency fund (should have occurred prior to # 1, but just didn&#39;t officially set it aside as such.)



&lt;ul&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;4 months expenses in high-interest savings account, now adding $100/mo to build toward 5 months or anticipate future higher COL&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;/li&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;Contribute to tax deferred accounts up to max



&lt;ul&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;Last year (2015) I started contributing to 401(k) up to max&lt;/li&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;Not yet maxing out HSA since prefer to build up accessible funds in taxable account to help finance future small business (but putting enough into HSA to cover expected annual expenses--i.e. contact lenses and glasses.)&lt;/li&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;Not maxing out my Roth IRA for same reason as IRA, although plan to increase contributions with next pay increase&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Milestones to look forward to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;Next month, my total retirement + cash accounts should exceed the balance due on my mortgage loan&lt;/li&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;During June I should find out my next salary increase and nail down the adjustments I&#39;ll make to automatic savings plans&lt;/li&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;7 years from now, I could stop adding to retirement accounts, and just let them grow until I&#39;m 65 and likely have plenty of money to retire on (assuming I keep my spending rate about equal to now.) (I don&#39;t plan to stop contributing entirely.)&lt;/li&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;15 years from now, I could stop working and live off of savings, assuming:



&lt;ul&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;Salary keeps up with inflation&lt;/li&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;Keep earning steadily each year and don&#39;t take time off work for kids / travel / life.&lt;/li&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;Spending levels don&#39;t change&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of assumptions in hitting those milestones that I am already fairly certain will not be reality. It seems more likely than not (haha accountant-speak) that the plan should take into account both moving to a higher cost-of-living city at some point (to be closer to where we grew up) and the addition of children (which I would at a minimum take a few months off for, but preferably more time than that.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can make choices now to affect the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;Focus on a career path that will cause earnings to increase more rapidly



&lt;ul&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;For example, leveraging my way up to controller at a larger company, with employees under me, resulting in higher pay grade.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;/li&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;Figure out a career path that may pay less, but I would like to do for my whole life rather than just the next 15 years



&lt;ul&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;A. Could turn current skill set into a small business to allow flexibility (work fewer hours but work more years)



&lt;ul&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;Challenge here is that for years this will likely mean earning less per hour of work, which would be same effect as just finding an employer to let me work part-time. However, could eventually turn into much higher earning per hour, if successful, which working part time for a company likely will not.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;/li&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;B. Could learn a whole new skill and change careers to something that makes me not desire to retire early



&lt;ul&gt;



    &lt;li&gt;I&#39;m not sure there&#39;s anything out there that I really want to do for 40+ hours per week for decades&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2A seems like the most feasible plan to me, but pretty scary. It seems like the most interesting, but the least stable. And what if it turns out I don&amp;rsquo;t like it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really, I&amp;rsquo;m suffering from the good problem of having too many options. I could decide to change careers entirely in the next couple of years and still be fine for retirement&amp;ndash;problem is, I don&amp;rsquo;t really have an overriding passionate purpose I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting to pursue. Day-to-day, I know accounting work is up my ally, even if it isn&amp;rsquo;t all that interesting all of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mortgage update March 2016</title>
      <link>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2016-03-14-mortgage-update-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2016-03-14-mortgage-update-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I refinanced my mortgage in November. I got the rate dropped from 3.75% to 2.99% by switching to a 15 year mortgage and since my loan-to-value ratio is now way under 80%, thanks to paying down the loan, and the appraised value of the house increasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refinancing also comes with a bunch of fees, so if we end up moving in say, 3 years, the refinance would have barely been worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mortgage balance when I refinanced was at $110,238. After refinancing, with the fees (plus some padding in case they estimated the fees wrong), the principal balance went up to $115,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, before refinancing, I was paying $1,126/mo (which included a prepayment of $100/mo), so the monthly principal paid down was about $370/mo. After financing, my payment is $1,053/mo, about $510 of which is principal payment. So the balance will be back down to $110,391 by September. Now, some of the savings comes from no longer having to pay MIP, which would have dropped off in a year anyway. (So I would have been paying only $1,000/mo for the same $370/mo in principal.) My main regret is that I didn&amp;rsquo;t refinance months earlier, since even though I had not quite paid down 20% of the home value, the house appraised for over $100,000 more than it did when I bought it, so I would have been able to refinance to a PMI-free loan anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I calculate it, the net savings in interest and fees from the date of the refinance to 12/31/2018 is only $165. If we stay in the house through 12/31/2019, then we start to see more savings (about $596 more saved in interest). My S.O. is getting ready to graduate with his PhD sometime in the next couple of years, so it is unclear whether we will move then or not, or when exactly that will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other benefit is less tangible, but right before I refinanced, my mortgage was transferred from Chase Bank to Carrington Mortgage, which was a pretty terrible experience. There&amp;rsquo;s no guarantee how long the company I refinanced with will keep my loan for, but for now at least I am not dealing with a mortgage servicer that makes everything horrible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s going on</title>
      <link>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2016-03-10-what%27s-going-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2016-03-10-what%27s-going-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on writing a book. I was doing pretty well at writing daily, and then last week I kind of stalled. I&amp;rsquo;ll write a bit after this. It&amp;rsquo;s the finishing that&amp;rsquo;s the problem. I&amp;rsquo;m not a good finisher in most cases, but in the case of writing a book, I think the final scenes should be just as fun to write as other scenes&amp;hellip; and if they&amp;rsquo;re boring to write, it probably means that they&amp;rsquo;ll be boring to read. Unfortunately, I think it&amp;rsquo;ll take a lot more practice to stop being boring when I write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my other domains got hacked and my hosting was shut down for a couple of days. So welcome back website! I learned that I don&amp;rsquo;t really know anything about websites or website security, but it seems like the hackers got in through an old theme or old plugin, so now I know to be on the lookout for themes or plugins that need to be updated, or that haven&amp;rsquo;t been updated in a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I switched from a Polar Loop for a FitBit Charge HR last month, and I am not regretting it. We have a group of work folks with them so we can all compare. This week I have to try and keep up with a coworker who is at Disney World for three days though, so I think I&amp;rsquo;ll fall out of the lead, but I&amp;rsquo;m trying to keep up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to read Stephen King&amp;rsquo;s Dark Tower series, but I keep putting it down and picking up 10 other books before I pick it back up again. It&amp;rsquo;s not that I don&amp;rsquo;t like it&amp;ndash;I can tell that he is good at keeping the action going so you don&amp;rsquo;t want to put it down while you&amp;rsquo;re reading. I think I just don&amp;rsquo;t identify enough with any of the characters to really care about what happens to them once I&amp;rsquo;ve put the book down. But, I always assumed I&amp;rsquo;d hate Stephen King since I don&amp;rsquo;t like horror, so it&amp;rsquo;s surprising to see how this series at least is really fantasy and barely horror at all. It makes me wonder if I don&amp;rsquo;t understand what the genre of horror really encompasses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, my new year&amp;rsquo;s resolution was to not buy any books for a year&amp;ndash;just to read what I already have piled up, or borrow from friends / the library. It&amp;rsquo;s been harder than I thought. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been to the library because I&amp;rsquo;ve had plenty of other things to read, but I spent a lot of my time re-reading old favorites instead of reading the piled-up books that I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to get to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been pretty successful at reading a bunch of Jane Austen novels, since those are available on Amazon.com as e-books for free. I still like North &amp;amp; South the best. (Saw the mini-series over the holidays, then read the book.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any suggestions of good books available for free on Kindle?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on aiming for early retirement</title>
      <link>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2015-08-08-thoughts-on-aiming-for-early-retirement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2015-08-08-thoughts-on-aiming-for-early-retirement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I first learned about early retirement about four years ago, in my first year of having a real job after college. I immediately knew that this was something I wanted to aim for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t on track to earn as much as say, Mr. Money Mustache did, early in his career, but accounting is pretty well-paid, and I live in a low cost-of-living area, relative to salaries, so it seemed like I should be able to make a plan and be financially independent well in advance of the traditional retirement age of 65.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, after five years of work, I think I could probably early retire in another seventeen years. (I am using what I believe to be &amp;ldquo;reasonable&amp;rdquo; expected rates of return, which are probably less aggressive than many other people doing this calculation.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find myself sitting here now with the following questions:
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;If I have another 17 years of work anyway, should I try to change careers to another career that&amp;rsquo;s more rewarding for those remaining years of work?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Should I try to find higher paying work that is more stressful, to retire sooner?&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;



&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Can I reasonably live a different lifestyle so as to retire sooner? Or is my lifestyle likely to just cost more, as we will likely move to a more expensive city and possibly have children during the next seventeen years?&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;



&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;What will I do when I early retire?&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;



&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Is early retirement the right goal? Maybe I should instead try to identify a career that is rewarding enough that I will &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;want&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; to go to work as long as I possibly can?&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;



&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;How should I plan for things that are best to enjoy, or can only happen, earlier in life (travel and kids)? i.e. Would have to take a break from work before 17 years have passed if I wanted to spend time at home with kids, and the return to work later.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have any answers yet, but I am exploring whether there exists another career path where I would be more excited to go to work every day. Otherwise, another compromise might be working as a consultant, but not full-time. This would be a great choice, except I&amp;rsquo;m starting to learn that typically opportunities where you only work say &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; of the time, usually pay less than &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; of the equivalent full-time salary. Anyone have any experience or thoughts on reducing workload?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax reform - Paying a fair share</title>
      <link>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2015-06-16-tax-reform---paying-a-fair-share/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2015-06-16-tax-reform---paying-a-fair-share/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw this campaign poster shared on Facebook this week:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.accountantbyday.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Bernie-Sanders-campaign-poster.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; size-medium wp-image-1265 alignleft&#34; src=&#34;http://www.accountantbyday.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Bernie-Sanders-campaign-poster-300x300.png&#34; alt=&#34;Bernie Sanders campaign poster&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you might expect (or maybe you don&amp;rsquo;t expect it), the effects of changing the tax code can be complex. The effects of changes in the tax code is the field of study for many accounting academics. In some cases, the effects are as-expected, and in some cases, not. For example, the mortgage interest deduction is intended to make homes easier for people to afford. In reality, average home prices simply increase to offset any savings from the deduction. This has been proven in several studies, however, the deduction is so popular with voters that it is unlikely to be removed any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with the poster above, is that it implies that it is &lt;strong&gt;possible&lt;/strong&gt; for the percent of federal tax revenue that is derived from corporate income taxes to be &lt;strong&gt;affected by changes to the tax code&lt;/strong&gt;. (Of course&amp;ndash;the poster could be implying a tax cut for individuals across the board&amp;ndash;if total tax revenues decreased, but corporation tax revenues stay the same, we would increase the corporate &amp;ldquo;share&amp;rdquo; of the tax revenues. But I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s what this poster is saying.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no tax researcher, but I suspect that this would be a very difficult number for the US tax code to change, since the companies contributing these tax revenues are operating in a global business environment. In fact, the global environment is likely the cause of much of the decrease in tax revenues received from corporations. If there is a more favorable tax code in another country, these corporations and their teams of tax accountants can structure their business to take advantage of this. If the US tax on corporations increases, I would imagine that the corporations would find a way to shift even more of their taxable revenue to other countries. Of course, in order to keep operating in the U.S., these businesses will have to pay some tax here, but I do think this is a particularly tough battle to take on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, a corporation may have branches in Country A and in the U.S., where Country A has a more favorable effective tax rate. Imagine that the final market in the U.S. is willing to pay $100 per unit for the final product. The branch in Country A may manufacture the product at a cost of $10, and can &amp;ldquo;sell&amp;rdquo; it&amp;rsquo;s U.S. branch the products at $80/unit, realizing a profit $70/unit in Country A, and only $20/unit in the U.S. Worldwide, the true profit per unit is $90, but the US only receives tax on $20. So there are &lt;strong&gt;transfer pricing&lt;/strong&gt; laws that address what a reasonable sales price between the Country A branch and the U.S. branch could be. But these laws can only provide guidelines for reasonableness, and besides, as many resources as the IRS can devote to investigating specific corporations to ensure that they comply with these laws, the corporations can undoubtedly put additional resources of their own towards circumventing the spirit of the law in a legal manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, corporations are going to do all that they can to pay the minimum tax possible. Maybe the U.S. tax rate is too high?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a simplified example, with some fake tax rates:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Country A has a tax rate of 20%, vs an effective tax rate for this particular corporation of say, 25%, then if the U.S. lowers its tax rate to say, 19%, the corporation would be better off paying taxes to the U.S. &lt;em&gt;instead of&lt;/em&gt; Country A. If the corporation then allocates $70 of profit t to the U.S. ($70 x 19% = $13.3 tax revenue) instead of only $20 at a rate of 25% ($20 x 25% = $5 tax revenue), the U.S. would receive more total tax revenue. So that&amp;rsquo;s one possible way to address the situation. But what if Country A&amp;rsquo;s tax rate is only 5%? The U.S. is better off only taxing $20 of profit at 25% ($5) than taxing $70 of profit at 5% or less ($3.5).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To summarize, the U.S. might be able to shift more tax revenue to the U.S. by reducing corporate tax rates, but not if the rate needed to attract corporations to allocate more revenue to the U.S. is too low, relative to the amount of additional profit to be taxed. (This &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bloombergview.com/quicktake/profit-shifting-avoid-tax&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bloomberg article&lt;/a&gt; has more thoughts on tax inversion and also some links to various politician&amp;rsquo;s proposals to address the issue.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, what about small corporations that are not large enough to have international locations and a team of tax accountants? These corporations are paying the high tax rate on 100% of their profits already. Lower the corporate tax rate, and you lower the tax revenue from these companies too. Of course, perhaps they&amp;rsquo;ll take their tax savings, invest in their businesses, and ultimately generate more taxable income. Perhaps, instead, owners will sell their businesses sooner, since they are worth more, and take advantage of low capital gains tax rates to retire earlier than they would have otherwise&amp;ndash;and that is yet another example of how difficult it is to quantify the effects of tax policy changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun stuff, right? I certainly don&amp;rsquo;t have any answers. And, for the record, Bernie Sanders is addressing tax reform from many other angles, especially tax reform for individuals, which seems like it might have more direct results on Americans. I&amp;rsquo;m not expressing an opinion on his politics, nor am I saying there is or is not a need for tax reform&amp;ndash;I was just struck by the message of the poster, and wondered if it the % of tax revenues contributed by corporations is something a future President could change.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold calling</title>
      <link>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2015-06-12-cold-calling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2015-06-12-cold-calling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At our public accounting firm, our &amp;ldquo;business development&amp;rdquo; team had to cold call potential clients. I sat next to the office of a particularly loud BD team member for awhile, and the calls sounded pretty painful. He was an accountant-turned-salesperson, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a pretty transition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where I work now, I share an office with our admin, who also answers all of the calls made to the main company phone line. I would say that at least 80 percent of our calls are people trying to sell us something. They call back again and again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.accountantbyday.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Cobwebby-phone.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter wp-image-1262 size-medium&#34; src=&#34;http://www.accountantbyday.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Cobwebby-phone-300x293.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Vintage telephone covered in cobwebs&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;293&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see it working in some cases&amp;ndash;both the admin and I have fielded calls from &amp;ldquo;Breakfast with Bob&amp;rdquo; a guy who comes to businesses like ours and does soft skills training. We don&amp;rsquo;t pass his messages on to anyone, but if our boss suddenly decided we all needed soft skills training, maybe we&amp;rsquo;d remember Breakfast with Bob.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But so many of these companies use really poorly trained individuals, who just create a terrible company image. There was the lady who, when our admin said we weren&amp;rsquo;t interested in their service, said, &amp;ldquo;You obviously don&amp;rsquo;t know what you&amp;rsquo;re talking about&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;ll just call back later and talk to someone who knows what they&amp;rsquo;re doing.&amp;rdquo; Um? No one besides the admin is ever gonna answer your call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got one this week looking for one of our research engineers. Our admin said &amp;ldquo;Okay, do you want to leave a message and I&amp;rsquo;ll see if Joe can call you back?&amp;rdquo; The woman on the other end explains, &amp;ldquo;No. I have to call three times.&amp;rdquo; And then says goodbye and hangs up. Sounds like someone didn&amp;rsquo;t really understand their training?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the part that really surprises me is that, rather than making their pitch to the person who picks up the phone, they ask to speak &amp;ldquo;to the CEO.&amp;rdquo; Our admin is NEVER going to transfer their call to the CEO. They usually will leave their name and number, but not explain why he should call them back. So he&amp;rsquo;s NEVER going to call them back. Actually, he&amp;rsquo;s probably never even going to get the message. And yet the same ones will call over and over, insisting on speaking only to the CEO. Does that tactic ever work, anywhere? I guess it must, otherwise why is anyone paying them to make these calls?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stay on top of household expenses with HomeBudget</title>
      <link>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2015-05-18-stay-on-top-of-household-expenses-with-homebudget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2015-05-18-stay-on-top-of-household-expenses-with-homebudget/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay on top of household expenses with HomeBudget&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.accountantbyday.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Image1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter wp-image-1251 size-full&#34; src=&#34;http://www.accountantbyday.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Image1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image1&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;341&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Money management seems to be an issue that affects all classes. Several reports indicate that a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.com/news/business-32116356&#34;&gt;global recession&lt;/a&gt; will take effect sometime this year, so if there was a time that we needed to take care control of our finances, it’s now. Numerous programs are available online that can sort out your daily expenses and monthly bills, but why go through all that trouble when there are plenty of mobile financial apps that will allow you to clearly see where your income is going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems like smartphones can do anything these days. Owners of online slots portal &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spingenie.com/&#34;&gt;SpinGenie&lt;/a&gt; have said that mobile internet is the most prominent trend in the “internet landscape,” so budgeting with the help of an app is proven to be much more productive and accessible than you manually building expense reports on your personal computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a host of financial management apps currently on the market, with each having the intention of helping you organize your cashflow. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cnbc.com/id/102363544/page/1&#34;&gt;CNBC&lt;/a&gt; named 2015’s top ten money management mobile apps, but if there was one app that was readily applicable to any individual having difficulty tracking their monthly expenses it would be HomeBudget with Sync.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.accountantbyday.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Image2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter wp-image-1252 size-full&#34; src=&#34;http://www.accountantbyday.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Image2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image2&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For just a small fee, you can effectively manage your family’s income and cash outflow for optimum financial security. The app lets you add debit and credit accounts so that you can maintain your account balances for impending bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best feature about this app is that it can sync with multiple devices, allowing you and your family members to work off the same budget. Then you can export the data onto your computer to easily analysis your family’s monthly spending. That way, if your family’s ever short on funds at any given point, you’ll be able to manage finances so that it doesn’t occur again next month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HomeBudget with Sync is now available for download on &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/homebudget-with-sync/id578747615?mt=12&#34;&gt;the App Store&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.anishu.homebudget.full&amp;amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;Google Play&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Visit- How important is this step</title>
      <link>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2010-10-30-office-visit-how-important-is-this-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2010-10-30-office-visit-how-important-is-this-step/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Next week we will be having students coming into our accounting firm for their office visit interviews. This is the last round in the recruiting process, and in a matter of days, we will know who we will be having on board with us as spring and summer interns and future full-time hires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are going through the accounting recruiting process, the office visit may seem like one last hoop to jump through. At this point in the game, you&amp;rsquo;re probably tired and just want a job, any job. Well, keep putting in the effort, because the office visit is your chance to shine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The odds are in your favor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the students coming to our offices, we probably have positions for about &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; of them. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to be amazing to make it into that &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;, and if you come prepared and enthusiastic, I think you&amp;rsquo;d have a good chance of getting the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point in the process, everyone who gets an office visit is a perfectly viable candidate if they get good ratings from everyone at the firm. As far as I can tell, at this point, no one is worried about who&amp;rsquo;s GPA is the highest, or what extracurricular activities you did. They just want to meet you and get a feel for you. All you have to do is make sure that what they see is good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Live for the moment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will probably meet a lot of staff that you didn&amp;rsquo;t meet during the recruiting process. Our firm tries to make sure that, if possible, you are interviewed by a partner that has not yet gotten to know you. If you were only an average, not very memorable candidate during the social events, but made it to the office visit, you can wipe out your past history here. We will rate students after each day, and their most recent impression of you will be the one that decides how you score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, show up on time, come prepared with lots of questions, and be friendly to as many of the firm&amp;rsquo;s employees as you can!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$1000 a month debt payment plan</title>
      <link>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2011-12-14-$1000-a-month-debt-payment-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2011-12-14-$1000-a-month-debt-payment-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.accountantbyday.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/beach.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft size-medium wp-image-688&#34; style=&#34;margin: 10px 15px;&#34; title=&#34;OLYMPUS DIGITAL CAMERA&#34; src=&#34;http://www.accountantbyday.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/beach-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Palm tree and ocean&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This is the second month of my new debt-repayment plan. I&amp;rsquo;m paying off $1,000 plus each month, with the idea that my student loan will be paid off by November 2012. My student loan will be under $10,000 going into 2012, which is a great feeling!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial thoughts on the debt pay-off plan so far&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paying over $1,000/month towards my student loans really cramps my lifestyle. I hate the fact that by this time next year, I won&amp;rsquo;t be in any better position to buy a home, because I&amp;rsquo;m not putting any cash aside right now for a future down payment. I will be debt-free though - two and a half years after graduation. I only took out student loans for my final year of college, but it&amp;rsquo;s going to take me 2 years of working, even with a good salary, limiting my travel, eating out, and clothes shopping, in order to pay back the money I spent in one year as a student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I did take out these loans though, because it&amp;rsquo;s a fairly small amount of loan to pay off, but has really given me a taste for how easy it is to get in debt, and how difficult it could be to get out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting into debt is scarily easy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monthly pay outs make debt seem so much larger than the original borrowing ever was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, I set myself up with a credit card that had an introductory 0% APR for 12 months. We buy plane tickets and book hotel rooms on our own credit cards at work, and it can take a few weeks to get reimbursed. Since I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure I&amp;rsquo;d always have enough cash on hand in my own account to pay this off at the end of each month (if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t received reimbursement yet), I opened the 0% APR card so that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t need to pay any interest if I had to let a balance sit for awhile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in April last year, let&amp;rsquo;s say I had a balance of $2,000 of reimbursable expenses on the credit card. I received a reimbursement check for $2,000. But I decided to keep the cash from the check, and pay off the credit card a little bit each month, so that I would have more cash in the bank in case of an emergency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 0% rate expired on November 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;, so I had 6 months of payments. Even with a small debt of $2,000, that&amp;rsquo;s still over $300/month! I realized how much of a pain it was to pay that $333 each month. I realized that without sitting down and figuring out my monthly payments, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really have a great idea of how much delaying repayment would take out of my paycheck each month. It took more discipline to make the monthly payments, and to avoid using the extra cash in my bank account, than it would have to just repay the money with the reimbursement check to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, if you need help with debt management, there are plenty of companies and organizations out there that will help you develop a realistic &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.payplan.com/debt-management-plans.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;debt management plan&lt;/a&gt; that works for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debt in the future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point, I would like to be able to buy a house. Preferably sooner, rather than later. Right now, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I&amp;rsquo;ll still be living in the same place in five years, so I should probably wait to buy until then. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that will be my only debt acquired in the next 30-or-so years. And hopefully, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.payplan.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;debt management&lt;/a&gt; practices I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from these smaller debts will help me making paying off the mortgage a priority!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/shazwan/409580429/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Shazwan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2011 Goal Setting</title>
      <link>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2010-12-29-2011-goal-setting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2010-12-29-2011-goal-setting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What are you financial goals for 2011? Check out the poll in the sidebar to the right to participate!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/peasap/5300680841/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-113&#34; title=&#34;balloons peasap&#34; src=&#34;http://www.accountantbyday.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/balloons-peasap.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Goodbye 2010 Balloons&#34; width=&#34;534&#34; height=&#34;220&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the time of year where we review our past year and set some goals for the next year. I have many goals that I would like to list as New Years Resolutions, but goal-setting is generally more effective with fewer, specific, measurable goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010 in Review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During 2010, I graduated with my Masters of Accountancy, worked part time over the summer as a bookkeeper, worked part time as a research assistant for accounting professors and PhD students, passed my fourth and final part of the CPA exam, and started a full-time job in public accounting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What lies ahead in 2011&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2011, I&amp;rsquo;ll work through my first busy season as a full-time public accountant. I will, almost unavoidably, learn a huge amount about auditing and taxes. I should be eligible for my CPA license by the end of 2011.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I will accomplish&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Professionally - Accounting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2011, I would like to learn to become a better accountant. I will certainly learn during busy season, and I hear that I remain mostly confused until my second busy season has passed, but I hope that I will end the season with some feeling of competence at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a blogger&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to get AccountantByDay.com to an Alexa rank below 200,000 and make it into the Yakezie network! In order to accomplish this, I plan to post a minimum of 3 times per week, but ideally more. I will strive to improve my writing, and choose topics to write about that my readers find valuable. I also plan to devote plenty of time to building relationships with other bloggers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;As an artist (and a blogger!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently opened a store on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.etsy.com/shop/cecicooper&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Etsy.com &lt;/a&gt;to sell some of my artwork. I also have a blog that goes along with this venture (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cecicooper.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CeciCooper.com&lt;/a&gt;). This blog is pretty much at ground zero right now, so I have a lot of work ahead of me to network with other craft/arts bloggers and build a readership. As with AccountantByDay, I will focus on posting frequently, writing quality, valuable posts, and creating relationships with other bloggers in that sphere. As for the art, I hope to keep adding various products to my Etsy.com store. Apparently having at least 100 products nets you much more interest, so one of my goals is to reach 100 listed products over the next few months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on in 2011, I would like to launch a new site: HandmadeEntrepreneur.com. The viability of this website is somewhat dependent on my success as a seller of art, but the basic idea is to create a website for beginning sellers of handmade goods online to introduce them to the world of blogging to market their crafts. Soon I&amp;rsquo;ll be looking for a talented photographer to write some articles about taking better photographs of arts and crafts. My current goals for this website include: writing at least 25 pillar articles in various categories before launch, and also successfully building the readership of CeciCooper.com so I will have an audience to start with when the blog is launched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Financially&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1st: Establish an emergency fund that will cover 3 months of expenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2nd: Reduce my student loans to $10,000 (At 17,600 right now.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2rd: Put 60% of my paycheck towards my net worth (paying down debt, increasing investments, savings. Anything except spending.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accountability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a month, I plan to post updates on these goals here. Checking in with goals once a year is not enough to keep me feeling accountable!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that many of you have blog posts about your 2011 goals and plans. Let&amp;rsquo;s all keep each other updated on how well those goals are doing. With accountability and encouragement, I think that we&amp;rsquo;ll all be happy with how well we stick to our goals in the new year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.littlehouseinthevalley.com/2011-goals-part-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Little House in the Valley: 2011 Goals Part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://frugalzeitgeist.com/new-year-resolutions-finances-2011/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Frugal Zeigeist: New Year Resolutions: Finances 2011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.financialsamurai.com/2010/12/27/financial-samurai-goals-and-resolutions-for-2011/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Financial Samurai Goals and Resolutions for 2011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.consumerismcommentary.com/goals-and-resolutions-for-2011/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Consumerism Commentary: Goals and Resolutions for 2011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://savingmoneytoday.net/2010/my-goals-for-2011/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Saving Money Today: My Goals for 2011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pffirewall.com/family/years-resolution-declaring-2011-year-loose-ends/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PF Firewall: My New Years Resolution: Declaring 2011 the Year of Loose Ends&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://brianaford.info/pba/2011-resolutions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Briana Ford: 2011 Resolutions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/peasap/5300680841/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Photo by Peasap on Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways to Prepare for the Uniform CPA Exam</title>
      <link>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2013-01-06-5-ways-to-prepare-for-the-uniform-cpa-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2013-01-06-5-ways-to-prepare-for-the-uniform-cpa-exam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The infamously rigorous &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aicpa.org/BecomeACPA/CPAExam/Pages/CPAExam.aspx&#34;&gt;Uniform Certified Public Accountant Exam&lt;/a&gt; is, of course, among the fundamental requirements for CPA licensure in all jurisdictions. The 14-hour-long, four-part exam is well known as the most arduous part of the proving grounds that ultimately lead to professional opportunities, increased pay, and personal fulfillment through CPA licensure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you&amp;rsquo;ve looked into the seemingly endless array of books, prep courses, video tutorials and podcasts designed to help you achieve that all-important passing score, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely found that even finding the best place to turn for help in preparing for the exam can be a challenge. Fear not – we’re here to help!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you’ll find 5 steps that every student accountant with CPA aspirations should take when preparing for the CPA exam:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Contact your state’s Board of Accountancy to verify your eligibility to sit for the exam.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you’re confident that you’ve met all the requirements set forth by your state&amp;rsquo;s Board of Accountancy to sit for the exam, you’ll still need to contact your Board directly to be deemed eligible. In most cases you’ll be required to complete an application, submit references, and provide the Board with sealed college transcripts. To research and gain an overview of state by state requirements visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.accountingedu.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Accounting Edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although your state’s Board of Accountancy sets specific CPA licensing requirements within your state, under the Uniform Accountancy Act (UAA) most states have similar requirements. In general, you can expect to be required to meet specific education, examination and experience requirements, often referred to as the “3 Es”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education&lt;/strong&gt; - Usually requires a bachelor’s degree at minimum and a total of 150 semester hours of relevant college-level courses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Examination&lt;/strong&gt; – Always requires passing scores on all four parts of the Uniform CPA Exam&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experience&lt;/strong&gt; – Usually requires one-year minimum accounting experience within a CPA firm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Educate yourself on the entire process.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fully prepared to take the Uniform CPA Exam, you’ll need to know what you’re getting yourself into. As you already know, the stakes are far too high to take this on without some serious preplanning. Get started by reading the &lt;em&gt;CPA Candidate Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;, which is available online through the American Institute of CPAs (AICPA).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;CPA Candidate Bulletin&lt;/em&gt; is updated to a current version each year, and includes detailed information on how to apply for the exam; how to schedule the exam once you’ve been approved to take it; as well as information on where, when and how to receive your scores after completing the exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Familiarize yourself with the scope of the examination.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preparing for the Uniform CPA Exam starts by getting a firm grasp on what material will be covered in each of the four sections:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Auditing and Attestation (AUD)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Financial Accounting and Reporting (FAR)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regulation (REG)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Business Environment and Concepts (BEC)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AICPA provides this information to all CPA exam candidates on their website through &lt;em&gt;Content Specific Outlines (CSOs).&lt;/em&gt; The CSOs contain all areas, groups and topics to be tested, thereby allowing you to best strategize your exam preparation. No one wants to be surprised by unexpected test material on exam day, so thoroughly reviewing the current CSOs is always in order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Take the AICPA tutorial and sample tests.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AICPA has a great section on their website that allows you to become familiar with the scope, format and functionality of the exam, as well as sample tests that allow you to better understand how to complete the exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the tutorial does not contain any exam content, it does allow you to understand the type of questions on the test, as well as how to best navigate the exam. The sample tests provide an interactive environment where you can take all the time you need to become comfortable with the structure, organization, and layout of the exam from the comfort of your home (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aicpa.org/BECOMEACPA/CPAEXAM/FORCANDIDATES/TUTORIALANDSAMPLETEST/Pages/exam_tutorial_parallel.aspx&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; for tutorials and sample tests from AICPA.org).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Research the best way to study for the exam.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have verified your eligibility to sit for the exam, familiarized yourself with the exam’s overall format and function and have carefully reviewed the most recent CSOs, you will likely have a clear idea of what areas you most need to brush up on. This is where you should focus your attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many channels through which you can to study for the CPA exam, including seminars, online courses, and published review materials. Any of these options is as good as another in terms of proving a thorough review of exam content. What you really need to take into consideration is what learning methods tend to work best for you before you purchase any costly study materials or sign up for an expensive course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may come across a number of recommendations from fellow students, colleagues or faculty members, as well, so keep your eyes open for study opportunities and obtain the advice of a trusted faculty member if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that forethought, planning, and unavoidably – hours of study, lay the groundwork for success on the Uniform CPA Exam!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 reasons to hire a payroll company</title>
      <link>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2012-03-13-5-reasons-to-hire-a-payroll-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2012-03-13-5-reasons-to-hire-a-payroll-company/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many of the clients I work with are foreign companies expanding to a new location. There are many things a new company needs to have on it&amp;rsquo;s to-do list - applying for a tax id number, selecting a site to locate their business, payroll services - but one of the top items on the list of any new business, whether foreign or domestic, should be hiring &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.modina.co.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;payroll services&lt;/a&gt; to make sure that your employees are paid in a timely fashion and in accordance with local laws and tax codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? Because you need to pay your employees of course! Payroll is a complex process, and every country has different rules. I can&amp;rsquo;t think of a single client I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with that does their own payroll in-house. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to shop around for payroll services though - just because a company is big and famous does not mean that it is the right payroll service provider for your business!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why should you hire a payroll company? Isn&amp;rsquo;t that just another cost to add to your company&amp;rsquo;s expenses?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid the hassle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are running a small business, chances are, you don&amp;rsquo;t have time to keep track of payroll yourself. Hiring another employee isn&amp;rsquo;t worth it either, since payroll processing most likely won&amp;rsquo;t be a full-time job at a small company. Save yourself the time and effort of having to become a payroll expert instead of working on your business. Most companies find it to be more cost effective to hire an outside service for these duties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hiring an expert&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Payroll comes along with many moving parts. Employers need to withhold taxes from their employees&amp;rsquo; paychecks, accrue for accumulated vacation time employees earn, and keep track of any advances or withholding from employees&amp;rsquo; pay. Employers also need to make sure that everyone&amp;rsquo;s check is cut on time and makes it to the right employee in a timely fashion. A good payroll company will know the laws of the country it operates in, as well as any specifics of the state/regions that your employees are working in. Their employees should be well-trained in the running of payroll, and managers should oversee their work. Chances are, your in-house employees won&amp;rsquo;t be as savvy as an employee of a firm that does nothing but payroll all day long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced technology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your typical payroll service provider will offer your employees perks that would most likely be difficult for your small business to provide, such as direct deposit, and secure electronic paystubs. Most of my coworkers and I prefer and to receive our pay checks and pay stubs electronically. This method of paying employees is commonplace and expected from employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Separation of duties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a small business with only one or two employees handling the accounting, it can be very difficult to create enough separation of duties to prevent any one employee being able to commit fraud. By outsourcing the payroll process, you will be able to separate this vulnerable area away from any accounting employee that may already have access to many other accounting functions. An employee that keeps the accounting books, cuts the checks, and keeps track of payroll could easily add fictitious employees to the monthly payroll without vigilant oversight from a manager. Rather than keeping an eagle eye on the employee, outsourcing payroll can prevent some potential frauds from arising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add-on services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many payroll companies offer additional services that you may find that your business needs as it grows. Since it makes sense to hire a payroll company right from the start, you will have the added benefit of developing a relationship with the company so that you can feel comfortable putting other services in their hands - such as bookkeeping and other accounting services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Convinced yet? Ask around a few other business owners in your area to see what choice they made to help you make your decision of whether to outsource payroll. You may be surprised how many of these businesses use outside companies to handle this function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A certain and unworried time</title>
      <link>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2012-07-22-a-certain-and-unworried-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2012-07-22-a-certain-and-unworried-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just read an essay by F. Scott Fitzgerald looking back on the Jazz Age two years after the stock market crash in 1929 (&amp;rdquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dlackey.org/weblog/docs/Echoes%20of%20the%20Jazz%20Age.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Echoes of the Jazz Age&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;ldquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following lines caught my imagination:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; it was pleasant to be in one&amp;rsquo;s twenties in such a certain and unworried time. Even when you were broke you didn&amp;rsquo;t worry about money because it was in such profusion around you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I counted the years and realized that 4 of the 5 years of my twenties that I have lived so far have been during the recession. Despite having a good job in a strong industry, the anxiety of how quickly all of that can be lost is going to color my twenties the way a boom time affected the lives of young people during the 1920&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, most people in the 1920&amp;rsquo;s probably didn&amp;rsquo;t live the lives that F. Scott Fitzgerald and Ernest Hemingway and that group did, but by contrast, I certainly live my life with much more preoccupation with money than they did, and much less preoccupation with &lt;em&gt;living&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;creating&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder which of us had/will have more regret in the decade following our twenties. Following the Jazz Age, the stock market crashed, making money, and the shortage of it, an international concern. It would be the perfect inverse for the decade following my twenties to be one of economic boom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A comment on Todd Aiken&#39;s comments</title>
      <link>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2012-08-21-a-comment-on-todd-aiken%27s-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://accountantbyday.com/post/2012-08-21-a-comment-on-todd-aiken%27s-comments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I know it&amp;rsquo;s yesterday&amp;rsquo;s news, and I also usually don&amp;rsquo;t bring up politics on this blog, but I am also a woman, and I think that Todd Aiken&amp;rsquo;s comments, and the anti-abortion laws that have been creeping into legislation all over our country in the past couple of years are something we need to discuss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with someone like Todd Aiken getting up and making such offensive comments - namely that someone can distinguish between &amp;ldquo;legitimate rape&amp;rdquo; and, apparently, any other kinds of rape and making the completely false statement that women&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rsquo; bodies will prevent the woman from getting pregnant. The problem with such inflammatory comments is that someone who is still pretty conservative on this issue can get up and say &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s ridiculous, I fully support abortion rights in cases of rape.&amp;rdquo; And they sound reasonable. Except what they&amp;rsquo;re also saying is that they don&amp;rsquo;t support abortion in any cases OTHER than rape. But because they don&amp;rsquo;t sound as crazy as Todd Aiken, their statement seems like a much more understandable sentiment, and pretty soon, this becomes a much more popular view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is a slippery slope. Even if you think abortion shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be allowed unless the pregnancy is a result of rape - how do you plan to have the woman prove that? Then we will have a society where women will be forced to prove that a crime was committed, when we all know how difficult that has been to prove in many cases for the criminal-prosecution side of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cannot allow the small infringements on women&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rsquo; rights to pass without comment - such as a the mandated ultrasounds in states like Texas, Oklahoma, and North Carolina - or they will just set the stage for bigger infringements to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>